Tatiana Patrusheva

Apex, NC · 984-303-1114 · <u>patrushevtaitana@gmail.com</u>

DATA SCIENTIST

I am a Data Scientist with experience in both R and Python, I enjoy delivering projects on time and continuously improving my skill set. During my work as a Data Analyst, I acquired valuable skills in data cleaning and pattern recognition. Additionally, my past experiences in Biotechnology and IT equipped me with valuable communication and teamwork skills, enabling me to work efficiently with diverse teams and stakeholders.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Python, R, SQL

MACHINE LEARNING: Regression, Classification, Natural Language Processing (NLP), Time series forecasting, Tensorflow.

SOFTWARE: Power BI, Jira, GitHub, QlikView, JupyterLab

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Data Science Fellow

General Assembly, Remote

11/2022 - 03/2023

- Created six projects using different machine learning algorithms and techniques like Lasso, Ridge, XGBoost, Stacking, Tensorflow, Natural Language Processing, and Greykite.
- Presented to technical and non-technical audiences my findings.
- Acquired, Cleaned, Analyzed, and Modeled data using Python

Data Analyst

Eridge Underwriting Agency Limited, Tunbridge Wells, England, UK 04/2022 - 10/2022 Analyzed car insurance data using **R**, QlikView, Microsoft Power BI, and Microsoft Excel to identify trends and determine the sources of revenue reduction.

- Developed an automated report to analyze discount trends, resulting in a reduction of underwriting time spent on low-performing discounts.
- Identified the root cause of the plummeted performance of a broker.
- Cleaned and prepared the data for business reports.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Tester, Mail.Ru Group, Moscow, Russia

01/2014 - 10/2014

One of the leading Russian software development companies.

- Collaborated with front-end developers and the QA team to manually test iOS applications.
- Created Mind maps and Test Cases.
- Chose mobile devices for testing.

Mobile QA, NeoSphere, Moscow, Russia 07/2012 - 12/2013 NeoSphere developed different mobile applications: TV programs, applications for conferences, online chess matches, and a game. Was the first QA on the team.

- Created a quality assurance process.
- Assessed the quality of Android, iOS, WP, and Bada applications.
- Created Mind maps and Test Cases.
- Chose mobile devices for testing.

Engineer, Hematological Scientific Center, Moscow, Russia The laboratory investigated hematological malignancies.

07/2012 - 12/2013

- Worked on flow cytometer BD FACSCalibur.
- Immunophenotyped cells in the blood and bone marrow (cancer cells).
- Prepared samples and solutions.

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

- Data Analyst in SQL, DataCamp, 10.2022
- Machine Learning Scientist with Python, DataCamp, 09.2022
- Data Analyst in Power BI, DataCamp, 06.2022
- DataScientist with R, DataCamp, 06.2022
- BiostatisticcsL, edX, 02.2022
- Data Scientist Career Path, Codecademy, 11.2021
- Learn SQL Course, Codecademy, 11.2021
- Visualize Data with Python Skill Path, Codecademy, 11.2021
- Analyze Data with Python Skill Path, Codecademy, 01.2021

EDUCATION

Data Science, General Assembly, Remote

11/2022-03/2023

Engineer in Biotechnology (equivalent to US Master's Degree), Mendeleyev University of Chemical Technology of Russia, Moscow, Russia 09/2005-07/2010